My name's Conan Edogawa!
اسمي إيدوغاوا كونان
High school student Shinichi was forced to take a pill that shrunk him!
أُجبر مُتحرّي الثانوية كودو شينتشي على تجرّع عقار قلّص جسده
Doesn't matter if I'm small!
لا يهم صغر بنيتي
My mind is that of a former great detective!
!فعقلي هو عقل مُتحرٍّ عظيم سابق
Today's case takes place at an art museum!
!قضيّة اليوم تقع أحداثها في متحف فنون
Behind the scenes is a grisly, red death!
!خلف اللوحات الفنّية موت أحمر مروع
No matter the incident, there is always only one truth!
!مهما كان نوع القضيّة، الحقيقة واحدة دوماً
Medieval Art Exhibit
معرض فنّ القرون الوسطى
Patrolling an art museum at night is the last thing I wanted to do!
حراسة معرض فنون ليلاً هي !آخر ما أردته
You'll never make a good watchman with an attitude like that.
لن تصبح حارس أمن جيد بتفكير كهذا
Did you just hear something?
ألم تسمع شيئاً؟
P-Please don't tease me like that, sir!
أ-أوقف هذا رجاءً يا سينباي
I-It came from this room...
أ-أتى من هذه الغرفة
Who's there?!
!مـ-من هناك؟
Is there someone in here?
أيوجد أحد؟
A medieval suit of armor? All by itself?
درع قرون متوسطة؟ بنفسه؟
Two watchmen saw it!
رآه حارسان
Everyone's talking about it!
!الجميع يتكلم عن الأمر
What do you say we all go there right now? It sounds interesting!
لمَ لا نذهب نحن الثلاثة الآن؟ !يبدو الأمر مثيراً
The museum obviously cooked that story up to bring in more visitors!
اختلق المتحف تلك القصة لجذب مزيد من الزوّار حتماً
Yeah, Ran! Only kids would fall for that!
صحيح يا ران، سينطلي ذلك على الأطفال فقط
And you're not a kid all of a sudden?
!كلام من طفل
Well, time to get to work.
حسنٌ، وقت العمل
Guess I'll do my homework.
سأنجز فرضي المدرسي
Not so fast!
!توقّفا
Coming?
سنذهب، صحيح؟
Yes!
!أجل
Ran always gets like that when she gets mad.
تفعل ران هذا دوماً عندما تغضب
Shouldn't have let her learn karate.
كان علي ألّا أدعها تتعلم الكاراتيه
Look at all these beautiful paintings!
!انظروا لكلّ هذه اللوحات الجميلة
I'm so glad we came!
!أنا مسرورة لقدومنا
Look at this! The colors are so lovely!
!انظرا لهذه! ألوانها جميلة
I take it you like that painting, Miss?
أعجبتك اللوحة يا آنسة؟
I, too, enjoy this painting very much.
أنا أحب هذه اللوحة كثيراً أيضاً
No, I love all of the paintings here!
بالأحرى أحب كلّ اللوحات هنا
Almost as if they were my own children.
كما لو كانت صغاري
Who might you be?
عذراً، من أنت؟
Oh, where are my manners?
يا لفظاظتي
My name is Ochiai. I run this art gallery.
أنا مدير هذا المعرض الفنّي، اسمي أوتشياي
Oh! I should have known!
!المدير! كان عليّ أن أعرف
Please enjoy your visit here.
استمتعي بزيارتك رجاءً
Kubota! What are you doing?!
!كوبوتا! ما الذي تفعله؟
How many times have I said to wear gloves when handling exhibits?!
!أخبرك دوماً أن ترتدي قفازات عند لمس المعروضات
I-I'm sorry!
!آ-آسف
You can go.
يمكنك الذهاب
Iijima-kun. Please take over for him.
إيجيما-كن، اعتن بهذه نيابة عنه
Yes, sir.
حاضر
As empty and quiet as ever, I see.
فارغ وهادئ كالعادة
Mr. Manaka...
...المالك ماناكا
Ten days left until this place shuts down.
تبقت 10 أيام حتى إغلاق هذا المكان
Take care of all this moldy, old junk for me until then!
اعتن بهذه القمامة القديمة العفنة حتّى حينها
Okay, architect. Bring the blueprints.
حسناً أيّها المعماري، أحضر المخططات
Yes, sir.
حاضر
This art gallery is going to close for good?
سيُغلق هذا المعرض؟
Yes. The previous owner's company went bankrupt
أجل، أفلست شركة المالك السابق
so he sold this place to that Mr. Manaka.
فباع المعرض للمالك الجديد ماناكا
He sold it under the agreement that Mr. Manaka would keep it running!
باعه باتّفاق أن يحافظ ماناكا على المكان
But then the instant he bought it,
...لكن فورما اشتراه
he said he was going to turn it into a hotel!
!قال أنّه سيحول هذا المكان إلى فندق
He's carelessly handling another exhibit again.
يعامل المعروضات بإهمال مُجدداً
I take it you're Kubota-kun?
أنتَ كوبوتا-كن، صحيح؟
I've heard about you.
سمعت عنك
I suggest you hurry and scrape whatever money you can get together!
أقترح أن تسرع بجمع أكبر ما يمكنك من المال
Damn it!
!تبّاً
Again?!
!مُجدداً؟
Please enjoy your visit.
حسناً، استمتعوا بزيارتكم رجاءً
Why didn't he get angry again just now?
لماذا لم يغضب هذه المرّة؟
Earth Gallery
معرض الأرض
Sky Gallery
معرض السماء
Sea Gallery
معرض البحر
Huh?
ماذا؟
No entry.
الدخول ممنوع
That's strange. There's supposed to be another room up ahead.
غريب، يُفترض أن هناك حجرة أخرى أمامنا
Just forget about it. Let's hurry and get through this place.
تجاهليها، لننته سريعاً ونخرج من هنا
So tired!
أشعر بالإرهاق
Let's go home, Ran.
لنرجع يا ران-نيتشان
I'm starving!
أتضوّر جوعاً
Talk about pathetic! Getting exhausted so easily like this!
!أنتما مثيران للشفقة! تتعبان بهذه السهولة
Huh?
ماذا؟
The no entrance sign is gone.
اختفت لافتة المنع
Hey! Since we're here, why don't we go see the last room?
اسمعا، لمَ لا نذهب لرؤية الغرفة الأخيرة بما أننا هنا؟
You can go home if you want,
يمكنكما العودة إن أردتما
but you'll have to cook dinner yourselves.
لكنكما ستحضّران العشاء بمفردكما
That's not fair!
!ليس منصفاً
Hell Gallery
معرض الجحيم
This room sure is dark...
هذه الغرفة حالكة الظلام
Well, it is the Hell Gallery.
لهذا هو معرض الجحيم
What a huge picture!
!لوحة عملاقة
It literally is a picture from Hell.
كأنّها لوحة من الجحيم فعلاً
The title is "Divine Punishment."
"حسناً، العنوان هو "عقوبة سماوية
It says it's a picture of a knight of justice sealing away a demon.
مكتوب أنّها لوحة قام فيها فارس عدالة بالختم على شيطان
It's Mr. Manaka, the owner!
!المالك ماناكا
You again?!
أنت مجدداً؟
Yes, sir!
!أجل
I assure you, I haven't allowed anyone to touch the corpse, Inspector!
!لم أسمح لأحد بلمس الجثة بالطبع سيّدي المفتش
So, did anyone see who did it?
أرأى أحدكم المجرم إذاً؟
No. I've checked with everyone, but no one saw a thing...
كلا، سألتُ الجميع لكن لا أحد
That security camera might have caught the person on tape!
!لعلّ كاميرات المراقبة التقطت شيئاً
Okay, here we go.
حسناً، ها هي
What a stupid murderer. Being caught on tape without knowing it...
يا للمجرم الأحمق، يتم تصويره دون أن يدري
Oh? It's the owner!
!إنّه المالك
Time to come out, killer!
!فلتخرج أيّها القاتل
Let us have a good look at your face--
...دعنا نرى وجهك جيّداً
Wait a second!
...تمهل
I've seen this scene somewhere before!
رأيتُ هذا المشهد من قبل
It's exactly like in that painting!
!كتلك اللوحة تماماً
What painting?
تلك اللوحة؟
The picture on display directly across from the victim.
المعلقة مقابل الضحية
The title was "Divine Punishment."
"عنوانها كان "العقوبة السماوية
The murderer must have killed him in this manner
تعمد المجرم قتله بذاك الشكل
to make it look exactly like that painting.
كي يطابق اللوحة بالتأكيد
What a daring murderer, though.
لكن يا له من قاتل جريء
It would be all over if someone saw them wearing that around.
كان أمره سينتهي لو رآه أحد يرتدي ذاك الدرع
Now that you mention it, there was a no-entry sign in front of the room.
صحيح، كانت هناك لافتة منع دخول أمام تلك الغرفة
What now?
ماذا؟
Ran. That was around 4 o'clock, wasn't it?
ران، كان ذلك عند قرابة الرابعة، صحيح؟
But when we passed by just after 5:00, the sign was gone.
لكن عندما ذهبنا هناك بعد الخامسة كانت قد اختفت
The murder took place at approximately 4:30.
وقعت الجريمة قرابة الرابعة والنصف
It would seem it was the murderer who put the sign up.
يبدو أنّ المجرم هو من وضع تلك اللافتة
After doing that to keep people away,
،بعد فعل ذلك لإبعاد الناس
the murderer put the armor on and hid in the room.
ارتدى المجرم الدرع واختبأ في تلك الغرفة
And then killed Mr. Manaka.
ثمّ قتل ماناكا
Which means the killer was someone well-acquainted with the museum.
مما يعني أنّ القاتل شخص مُلم بالمتحف
In other words...
...أي
...the killer is one of you.
القاتل أحدكم
Hey, look! The owner's doing something!
!انظروا! المالك يفعل شيئاً
Hey, you! Don't be messing with the tape without permission!
!أ-أنت! لا تعبث بالتصوير بلا إذن
Look! He's doing something before the killer jumped out...
!انظروا، إنّه يقوم بشيء قبل انقضاض القاتل عليه
He realized something and took that card!
!صحيح، أدرك شيئاً وأخذ تلك البطاقة
And then the pen on top of the desk!
!ثم القلم فوق الطاولة
He's writing something!
!إنّه يكتب شيئاً
He threw the pen away!
!رمى القلم
What about the card?!
ماذا عن البطاقة؟
Crumpled up in his hands!
!مطوية في يديه
Does that card say what I think it might?
...أيمكن أنّ تلك البطاقة
It might still be in his hand!
لا تزال في يده؟
I found this piece of paper in the victim's hand.
وجدتُ هذه الورقة بيد الضحية
What's this?!
!ما هذا؟
K-Kubota!
!كـ-كوبوتا
W-What's my name doing on that?!
!لـ-لمَ اسمي مكتوب؟
It seems you wore the armor to conceal your identity from the camera,
ارتديت الدرع لإخفاء هويتك على كاميرات المراقبة
but it also seems that the victim wasn't so easily fooled!
لكن يبدو أنّ الضحية لم يكن سهل الخداع
N-No! It wasn't me!
!كـ-كلا! لم يكن أنا
In that case, give us your alibi. Where were you at 4:30?
أخبرنا بحجّة غيابك إذاً، أين كنت عند الرابعة والنصف؟
I was alone in the office, doing work that Mr. Ochiai asked me to do...
كـ-كنتُ بمفردي في المكتب أنجز العمل الذي كلفني به المدير
Yes, I did ask him to do some work.
أجل، طلبتُ منه إنجاز عمل
Then that means nobody saw you, doesn't it?
هذا يعني لم يرك أحد إذاً؟
Hold on! What motive would I have for killing the owner?!
!ا-انتظر رجاءً! ما دافعي لقتل المالك؟
There's no point in trying to talk your way out of this, Kubota-san!
لا جدوى من التحايل يا كوبوتا-سان
The owner threatened to sue you for damages
هدّد المالك بمقاضاتك للأضرار
because you were secretly selling this museum's exhibits!
!لأنّك كنت تبيع معروضات هذا المتحف سرّاً
Well, you see...
...هـ-هذا
Is this the truth?
أهي الحقيقة؟
But that had nothing to do with this!
!لـ-لكن... لا علاقة للأمر
I wasn't the one who killed him!
!لم أكن من قتله
If you say so.
لا يهم
The truth will come to light once my men find the suit of armor.
سنكتشف الحقيقة حال عثور أتباعي على الدرع
Inspector Megure! There's a ballpoint pen over here!
!مفتّش ميغوري! يوجد قلم برأس مدبب هنا
What?
ماذا؟
Excellent work, my boy.
أحسنتَ يا فتى
This is quite a nice pen!
يا له من قلم جميل
That pen was created this year
صُنع القلم هذا العام للاحتفال
in celebration of Beika Art Museum's 50th anniversary.
احتفالاً بالذكرى السنوية الخمسين لمعرض بيكا للفنون
Everyone who works here has one.
يحمله جميع العاملون هنا
So, someone accidentally left it here then?
نساه أحد هنا إذاً؟
Both colors and widths are exactly the same.
اللون والعرض متطابقان
This is probably the one the victim used.
إنّه القلم الذي استعمله الضحية على الأرجح
That's strange.
غريب
Kubota-san should have known about the security camera,
يُفترض أن كوبوتا-سان يعرف أمر كاميرات المراقبة
so why did he choose this room,
فلمَ اختار هذه الغرفة إن كان يتوجب عليه
especially if it meant wearing armor to conceal his identity?
ارتداء درع لإخفاء هويته؟
To make it look like that painting?
لجعل الجريمة مطابقة لتلك اللوحة؟
No, he doesn't seem to have much interest in art.
كلا، لا يبدو مهتماً كثيراً بالفنون
Would such a person actually do something like this?
هل يُقدم شخص مثله على شيء كهذا؟
Oh, man!
!تبّاً
It's straight out of a horror movie!
كأنّه مشهد من فيلم رعب
Hey there!
!يا عمّاه
Hey, little boy! You can't just barge in here!
!أيّها الفتى! لا يمكنك الدخول هكذا
Inspector Megure says he wants you to help with something else.
قال المفتش ميغوري أنّه يريد مساعدتكما في شيء آخر
He must've figured out we really wanted to watch the tape.
لا بد أنّه اكتشف أننا مهتمان برؤية التصوير
Well, let's get going.
لـ-لنذهب بأيّ حال
Right.
أجل
This is where it starts!
هذه البداية
What's with that expression?
ما خطب هذه التعابير؟
What's on the card that he's so shocked about?!
!ما الذي صعقه في تلك البطاقة؟
Why did he throw the pen away when he finished writing?
لمَ رمى القلم بعدما أنهى الكتابة؟
The killer would have realized he was there if he made any sounds...
كان القاتل ليسمع الصّوت
Wait! When I found the pen...
...لحظة، عندما وجدت القلم
...the tip was retracted!
!كان الرأس في الداخل...
Something's not right!
!غريب
It's unnatural for someone who's about to be killed
ليس من الطبيعي أن يعيد شخص
to retract the pen tip of a twist-style ballpoint pen!
!على وشك الموت رأسَ قلم حبر جافّ
Then maybe that means...
...ربما
Take care of the rest.
اعتنوا بالباقي إذاً
Yes, sir.
حاضر
Now, then...
...حسناً
Hey!
أنت
There's a mark on the paper!
!هناك علامة على الورقة
So, I was right.
كما ظننت
Now I have this trick figured out!
اكتشفتُ هذه الحيلة
Hey, you!
!أيّها الشقي
What do you think you're doing?!
!ما الذي تظن أنك تفعله؟
Inspector! We found it!
!وجدناه حضرة المفتش
We found the armor in Kubota-san's locker!
!الدرع في خزانة كوبوتا-سان
You found it?!
!وجدتماه؟
This is crazy! I don't know anything about this!
!لا-لا يعقل! لا أعرف شيئاً عن هذا
We have two major pieces of evidence that point to you!
يدينك دليلان الآن
This blood-smeared suit of armor, and the victim's dying message!
!هذا الدرع الملطخ بالدماء ورسالة احتضار الضحية
No! That isn't a dying message at all!
!كلا، لم تكن رسالة احتضار
It's a trick the killer used to put the blame on Kubota-san!
إنّها حيلة استعملها القاتل لتوجيه اللوم نحو كوبوتا-سان
That was one bloody attack.
هجوم دمويّ بحق
It's a shame that this work of art was ruined.
من المؤسف أنّ هذه القطعة الفنية أُفسدت
Actually, that's a replica used for decoration purposes.
كلا، إنّه تقليد طبق الأصل لتزيين المكان في الواقع
I believe it was the same one Kubota-san was moving this afternoon.
كان نفس الذي نقله كوبوتا-سان ظهيرة اليوم
Oh, that one?
ذاك؟
Ah, so it was a replica.
هكذا إذاً، كانت نسخة طبق الأصل
That's why the museum manager didn't say anything
لهذا لم يقل المدير شيئاً
when he handled the armor so violently.
.عندما عاملها كوبوتا-سان بقسوة
The replica was used in the attack, so the real one wasn't ruined.
استُعمِلت النسخة في الجريمة، لذلك لم يُفسد الدرع الحقيقي
It seems none of the other exhibits have been touched, either.
يبدو أنّ بقية المعروضات لم تُمس أيضاً
Come to think of it, the wall where he was killed...
...بالتفكير بالأمر، حائط الجريمة
...had cards, but no paintings!
به بطاقات، لكن لا لوحات
The killer removed them in advance.
أزالها القاتل مسبقاً
To protect them from the blood during the attack.
لحمايتها من الهجوم الدموي
The killer really was one of the staff members!
كان القاتل أحد عاملي المتحف بالفعل إذاً
Wait a second!
لحظة
This is a trick that doesn't work without nulling Kubota-san's alibi.
هذه حيلة لا تعمل دون إلغاء حجّة غياب كوبوتا-سان
Which means the one behind it...
...مما يعني أنّ الفاعل
...must be the museum manager!
!المدير بالتأكيد
If my conclusions are correct,
إن أصاب استنتاجي
there's a possibility the murderer might still have it...
فمن المحتمل أنّ القاتل لا يزال يحمله
Well, Kubota-san.
إذاً يا كوبوتا-سان
For now, you'll have to come down to the station.
لترافقنا للمركز حالياً
T-This can't be happening!
!لـ-لكن
I have to go bad!
!عليّ الذهاب بشدّة
Bathroom! Bathroom!
!الحمّام! الحمّام
Mister! Where's the bathroom?!
!أيّها العم! أين الحمّام؟
The restroom? Go out this room, go down the stairs on your right,
الحمّام؟ اخرج من هذه الغرفة ثم انزل من الدرج على يمينك
and then--
...وبعدها
That's too complicated for me!
!هذا معقّد كثير عليّ
Draw it on this!
!ارسم على هذه
Hurry up!
!بسرعة! بسرعة
As I said, you go out this room...
...أخبرتك، اخرج من هذه الغرفة
What's the matter, Mister?
ما الخطب يا عمّ؟
Why aren't you writing anything?
لمَ لا تكتب؟
Oh! You knew before writing anything that that pen doesn't work!
!فهمت! عرفت أنّ ذاك القلم لا يعمل قبل كتابة شيء
But that's strange. Why did you have a pen that you knew didn't work?
لكن هذا غريب، لمَ تحمل قلمَ حبرٍ جافّ تعرف أنّه لا يكتب؟
A ballpoint pen that doesn't work?!
قلم حبر جافّ لا يكتب؟
Hold on.
لحظة
If Mr. Manaka was also using a pen that doesn't work,
إن كان المالك ماناكا يستعمل قلماً لا يكتب أيضاً
then this dying message should be...
...فرسالة الاحتضار هذه يفترض أن تكون
...blank!
!فارغة
Look! There's a strange mark left behind!
!انظر! توجد علامة باقية غريبة
It looks like someone scribbled over the letters with a pen that didn't work!
كأن أحدهم خربش فوق الحروف بقلم لا يكتب
What if that mark was left behind
ماذا لو كانت علامات تُركت
because someone tried to cross out the letters beneath it,
،لأن أحداً حاول مسح الأحرف خلفها
but the pen didn't work?
لكن لم يعمل القلم؟
Who is this boy?!
!مـ-من هذا الصبيّ؟
Aha! This wasn't written by Mr. Manaka at all!
!هكذا إذاً! لم يكن المالك ماناكا من كتب هذه
It was written beforehand by none other than the killer!
!بل جهزها القاتل بنفسه سلفاً
But then why did he take the card in the first place?!
لكن لمَ أخذ المالك البطاقة من الأساس؟
Simple.
ذلك بسيط
The killer told the owner the following--
:أخبر القاتل المالك بالتالي
"Look at the card behind you! The name of your murderer is on it!"
"!انظر للبطاقة خلفك! اسم قاتلك عليها"
But the card had Kubota's name on it, not the name of the killer!
!لكن كان اسم كوبوتا على البطاقة، وليس القاتل
Shocked, he tried to cross out the name and replace it with the real one
حاول المالك المصدوم مسح الاسم واستبداله باسم الفاعل الحقيقي
using the ballpoint pen on the table.
باستعمال قلم الحبر الجافّ على الطاولة
But he couldn't.
لكنه لم ينجح
That pen had been placed there in advance by the killer,
فذاك القلم وُضع هناك سلفاً من قِبل القاتل
and it didn't work!
!ولا يكتب
So, that's why he threw the pen away and tried to crumple up the paper!
!لذا رمى القلم وحاول سحق الورقة؟
In short, this was all a trick to fool us, perpetrated by the killer
أي أنها كانت حيلة لخداعنا من تدبير القاتل
using a pen without ink and a video tape without sound!
!باستعمال قلم بلا حبر وتصوير بلا صوت
But the pen we found does work.
لكن القلم الذي وجدناه يكتب بلا مشاكل
Wasn't the tip of that pen retracted when we found it?
ألم يكن رأس القلم مسحوباً للداخل عندما وجدناه؟
Yes, now that you mention it...
...صحيح، معك حق
Strange for someone who's about to be killed
غريب، لمَ قد يرجع شخص على وشك الموت
to go through all the trouble of retracting a pen's tip...
رأس قلم حبر جافّ للداخل؟
So, the killer switched this pen with the other one after the murder,
بدّل القاتل هذا القلم بالآخر بعد الجريمة إذاً
but carelessly forgot to put the pen tip out?
لكن نسي إخراج الرأس إهمالاً؟
Which means whoever's currently in possession of a pen that doesn't work
مما يعني أن من بحوزته قلم لا يكتب حالياً
is the one responsible!
!هو الفاعل
In other words...
...أي
...it was you, Mr. Ochiai!
!أنت أيّها المدير أوتشياي
Let us hear your alibi.
هلّا أسمعتنا حجّة غيابك؟
Where were you at 4:30 when the murder took place?
أين كنت في الرابعة والنصف أثناء وقوع الجريمة؟
Mr. Ochiai...
حـ-حضرة المدير؟
I was waiting to meet someone at 4:30.
كنتُ أنتظر لقاء أحدهم عند الرابعة والنصف
Waiting for that black-hearted demon...
أنتظر ذاك الشيطان مظلم القلب
...while inside that suit of armor!
داخل ذاك الدرع...
Everything that happened afterward is exactly as you said, Detective.
ما حدث تالياً كان كما وصفت أيّها المتحري
Good thing everything was caught on tape!
من الجيد أنّ الكاميرات صورت كلّ شيء
That was no accident.
لم تكن صدفة
Having Mr. Manaka stand where he did, the timing,
،وقوف المالك حيث فعل، التوقيت
the location of the card, the location of the pen...
...موقع البطاقة ومكان القلم
They were all done according to my plan.
كلها كانت وفق خطتي
I practiced here on several occasions, you see.
فقد تدربت على هذا هنا عدة مرات
Then the rumor about the security guards
الشائعة عن رؤية الحرس
seeing the suit of armor walking late at night was real?!
!لدرع يمشي ليلاً كانت حقيقية إذاً؟
I felt it was a foolish thing to do,
شعرتُ أنّها فعلة ساذجة
but I did it for the purpose of getting rid of Mr. Manaka,
لكني أقدمت عليها للتخلص من المالك ماناكا
the demon who was going to shut down this divine museum
الشيطان الذي كان سيغلق هذا المتحف المقدّس
and take away from me all of these exhibits that are like my own children.
ويأخذ مني هذه المعروضات التي بمثابة أطفالي
And then there was Kubota-kun, who went and sold some of my exhibits.
وهناك كوبوتا-كن الذي باع مجموعةً من معروضاتي
I wanted to punish you as well.
أردتُ معاقبتك أيضاً
It appears to be different from the picture, Mr. Ochiai.
يبدو أنّ الأمر مختلف عن اللوحة يا مدير أوتشياي
It seems you've been struck down by divine punishment as well.
أُنزلت عليك عقوبة سماوية أيضاً
No, it is exactly like the painting.
كلا، كما في اللوحة تماماً
Although the knight of justice has slain the demon,
،رغم أنّ فارس العدالة قتل الشيطان
he has also been covered in its evil blood,
غطّته دماؤه الشريرة أيضاً
which will soak into him and make him wicked in turn.
مما أغرقه في الشرّ وأفسده
No matter how you look at it, I am a murderer.
مهما نظرت للأمر، أنا قاتل
I, too, have become a demon.
أصبحت شيطاناً بدوري
The fact that I was unable to deceive the small knight of justice
عجزي عن خداع فارس العدالة الصغير
is proof enough of this!
!هو برهان على ذلك
The small knight of justice?
فارس العدالة الصغير؟
Say, little boy. Do you not need to go to the restroom anymore?
لم تعد بحاجة للذهاب للحمام يا فتى؟
Eh? The art museum's not going to close after all?
ماذا؟ لن يُغلق متحف الفنون ذاك؟
Nope. The citizens all got together after they heard what happened.
كلا، تكاتف المواطنون بعدما سمعوا بالحادثة
That's good. We don't have many cultural spots around here, after all.
هذا رائع، فلا نملك الكثير من المراكز الثقافية هنا
I'm getting sick of this.
لكني سئمت
Sick of what, Genta-kun?
سئمت مماذا يا غينتا-كن؟
It's always Conan and that old man Kogoro!
!إنّهما العمّ موري وكونان دوماً
We never get to help out at all!
!لا دور لنا أبداً
Uh, that's because--
...ذ-ذلك
Oh yeah!
!صحيح
Have you heard the story at school
هل سمعتم بقصة هيكل
about the biology room skeleton coming to life at midnight?
غرفة الأحياء العظمي الذي يُبعث للحياة في منتصف الليل؟
Yeah, I've heard about that!
!أجل، سمعت عنها
One of the teachers saw it!
!رآه أحد المعلمين
But the heart was still...
...لكن كان القلب لا يزال
Okay! This is a case that calls for the Junior Detective Club!
!حسنٌ، إنّها قضية تطلب حضور فرقة فتيان التحرّي
Let's break into school later tonight!
!لنتسلل للمدرسة هذه الليلة
Hey, now...
!لحظة، رفاق
Conan! You better come too!
!كونان! عليك القدوم أيضاً
Give me a break!
!ارفقوا بي
There's no doubt about it! He's the murderer!
!لا شك! إنّه القاتل
But what's with that big smile?!
لكن ما خطب تلك الابتسامة العريضة؟
Just what sort of alibi does he have in that camera?!
أيّ حجة غياب في تلك الكاميرا بالضبط؟
Look! I took this!
انظر، التقطتُ هذه
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
The Tenkaichi Night Festival Murder.
جريمة قتل مهرجان تينكايتشي الليليّ
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Disposable Camera.
كاميرا قابلة للتخلص
Don't miss the next episode
!تحوي قضيّة الحلقة القادمة حيلة صادمة